whatismyipaddress.com 2018-12-17

# Privacy Policy

[Home](https://whatismyipaddress.com/)  »  Privacy Policy

WhatIsMyIPAddress.com would like to inform You how We protect Your privacy and use information We collect via this Website. This Privacy Policy is an agreement between You and CGP Holdings, Inc. d/b/a WhatIsMyIPAddress.com (hereinafter "WhatIsMyIPAddress"). Please read the terms of this Privacy Policy carefully.

If You do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy You may not use Our Website.

We may amend, add to, change, or modify the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy from time to time. Such amendments will be posted at this Webpage, and will take effect when posted. By continuing to use Our Website, or registering for a Forum Account on Our Community Forum, You agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and any amendments thereto. You further agree to the use of Your "Personally Identifiable Information" by Us in the manner specified in this Privacy Policy.

Each time You use the Website, the then-current version of this Privacy Policy will apply. Accordingly, each time You use the Website, You should check the date of this Privacy Policy (at the bottom of this page) and review any changes since the last time You used the Website. Although most changes are likely minor, WhatIsMyIPAddress.com reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy by posting such modification on this page; however, if changes are significant, WhatIsMyIPAddress.com may provide a more prominent notice. Unless WhatIsMyIPAddress.com obtains Your express consent, any revised Privacy Policy will apply only to information collected after the effective date of such revised Privacy Policy, and not to information collected under any earlier Privacy Policy.

We will never share Your personal information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in WhatIsMyIPAddress.com's Website Terms of Service located at <https://whatismyipaddress.com/terms-of-use>. This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Website and not to any websites of third-parties, which may have data collection, storage, and use practices and policies that differ materially from this Privacy Policy.

## 1\. INFORMATION COLLECTED

We collect two general types of information, "Non-Personally Identifiable Information" and "Personally Identifiable Information." We collect this information generally to improve Our Website and Your experience. We may sell, trade, rent, or transfer this information to third parties.

### a. NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

When You visit Our Website, We may collect some basic Non-Personally Identifiable Information about You. We collect non-personally identifiable information about You in a number of ways, including tracking Your activities through Your IP address, computer settings, or most-recently visited URL.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information is collected in order to provide You with satisfactory service and to improve Our Website. We may use the information to detect problems with Our server and to administer Our Website. In addition, Non-Personally Identifiable Information is compiled by Us and analyzed on an aggregate basis. We may sell, trade, rent, or transfer Non-Personally Identifiable Information to third-parties.

By using this Website, You agree to the publication of Your IP address on this Website.

Our Website is a location-aware website. When using Our Website, We may ask You to share information about Your location. If You voluntarily agree to share that information with Us, We will collect that information from nearby wireless access points and Your computer's IP address. We may sell that information to third-parties.

If You do not agree to share information about Your location with Us, We will not collect such information.

### b. PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

We do not collect any Personally Identifiable Information about You unless You voluntarily submit such information to Us, by, for example, agreeing to share Your location or registering for a Forum Account with Our Community Forum. This information lets Us know the specifics of who You are and can be used to identify, contact, or locate You.

Personally Identifiable Information may consist of: Your name, address, telephone number, email address, birth date, etc. By providing Us with Personally Identifiable Information, You consent to Our use of that information.

We use Personally Identifiable Information for internal purposes, such as analyzing trends and statistics and informing You of Our services. We may also sell, trade, rent, or transfer Personally Identifiable Information to third-parties.

Personally Identifiable Information is compiled by Us and analyzed on both a personal and an aggregated basis.

To serve You better, We may combine Personally Identifiable Information You give Us online. We may also combine that information with publicly available information about You that We may receive from third-parties.

We may contract with third-party companies or persons to provide certain services including data management, service of Our Website, etc. ("Service Providers").

We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services.

## 2\. REGISTERING FOR A WHATISMYIPADDRESS.COM COMMUNITY FORUM ACCOUNT

When You register for a WhatIsMyIPAddress.com Community Forum Account ("Forum Account") for access to Our Community Forum, You provide Us with Personally Identifiable Information.

Your Forum Account is password protected from third-parties. Your password is securely stored in Our database and cannot be retrieved. In the event that Your password is forgotten, You may reset Your password by visiting the login page and clicking "I forgot my password" and following the instructions to reset Your password.

You may edit Your Personal Information or account settings at any time by visiting the User Control Panel after a successful login to Your Forum Account.

Our Community Forum is powered by phpBB, which is a bulletin board solution released under the "GNU General Public License v2" and can be downloaded from www.phpbb.com. The phpBB software only facilitates Internet based discussions; phpBB is not responsible for what We allow and/or disallow as permissible content and/or conduct. For further information about phpBB, please see: https://www.phpbb.com/.

## 3\. PERSONAL INFORMATION PROVIDED BY YOU TO WHATISMYIPADDRESS.COM

In order for You to create a Forum Account for access to the Community Forum, You will be asked to provide WhatIsMyIPAddress.com certain information that personally identifies You. Personal Information includes, without limitation: Your e-mail address, website URLs, and instant messaging screen names. In each case, You will be asked to provide personal information. WhatIsMyIPAddress.com may supplement the personal information You provide with additional Personal Information gathered from public sources or from third-parties (e.g., consumer reporting agencies) who may lawfully provide such information to WhatIsMyIPAddress.

By creating a Forum Account, You are required to create a personal profile, which may include personal information. Personal information contained in personal profiles is available and accessible to other Community Forum members and visitors. The Community Forum contains features that permit You to upload, post, transmit, display, perform or distribute content, information, or personal information. Any information that You choose to disclose by means of such features becomes public information over which WhatIsMyIPAddress.com is unable to exercise control. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose Your personal information by means of such features, and You agree to assume all responsibility for doing so.

## 4\. CONSENT TO RECEIVE EMAIL COMMUNICATIONS

By creating a Forum Account, You thereby consent to receive email communications regarding Your account, the Community Forum, and other WhatIsMyIPAddress.com services.

By creating a Forum Account, You also consent to receive email communications, including email and private messages, from other Community Forum members. You may edit Your settings in Your Forum Account to disallow other Community members from contacting You by email or sending You private messages. To edit these settings, please access the User Control Panel and click on the "Board Preferences" tab.

## 5\. USE OF COOKIES AND CLEAR GIFS

When You view Our Website We might store some information on Your computer. This information will be in the form of a "cookie" or similar file. Cookies are small pieces of information stored on Your hard drive, not on Our Website. Cookies do not spy on You or otherwise invade Your privacy, and they cannot invade Your hard drive and steal information. Rather, they help You navigate a Website as easily as possible. We use cookies to deliver content specific to Your interests.

You have the ability to delete and control Cookies. If You do not wish to have Cookies placed on Your computer, You should set Your browsers to refuse Cookies before accessing the Website, with the understanding that certain Services and features of the Website may not function properly without the aid of Cookies. If You refuse Cookies, You assume all responsibility for any resulting loss of functionality.

You can learn more about how to delete or control cookies at www.aboutcookies.org.

Some of Our Service Providers may employ clear GIFs (also known as pixel tags, single pixel GIFs, web beacons or action tags) for Our benefit to help Us measure advertising effectiveness.

Clear GIFs help Us better manage content on Our Website by informing Us of what content is effective. Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Our users.

The main difference between the two is that clear GIFs are invisible on the page and are much smaller, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. Clear GIFs are not tied to Your Personally Identifiable Information.

Our Service Providers may use clear GIFs: (i) in HTML based emails to determine which emails have been opened by recipients; and (ii) to track the visitor traffic on Our Website.

These clear GIFs allow Us to measure the usage of Our Website by Our visitors and the effectiveness of certain communications and marketing campaigns. We may also use clear GIFs in a similar manner in Our own emails and on Our Website.

Clear GIFs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same website or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear GIF, the Website would match the clear GIFs identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer.

This collected information can be shared with the advertising company. We may provide such information to our Service Providers but that information can only be used by our Service Providers for Our benefit.

## 6\. AD SERVING

WhatIsMyIPAddress.com uses third-parties for pages that We host. These third-parties may place Cookies on Your computer, use web beacons, gather IP addresses, and log data to collect traffic and activity data in order to deliver relevant metrics, content, and advertising.

To opt-out of interest-based advertising please visit <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#!/>

## 7\. OTHER WEBSITES; LINKS

Our Website may contain links to other websites. These websites may have different privacy policies and practices from WhatIsMyIPAddress.com. WhatIsMyIPAddress.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. Accordingly, You access such linked sites at Your own risk. We urge You to follow safe Internet practices and do not supply Personal Information to these websites unless You have verified their security and privacy policies.

## 8\. DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURE

Most browsers offer Do Not Track (DNT) features that let You communicate to websites that You do not wish to be tracked around the web. DNT was designed to limit tracking across different websites and online services, and not data collection from websites You visit directly. Therefore, Our data collection and use is outside the scope of a DNT request.

## 9\. CHANGES TO YOUR FORUM ACCOUNT AND FORUM POSTS

If You would like to modify Your Forum Account, simply return to the Community Forum Website located at https://forums.whatismyipaddress.com/, and click on the link called "User Control Panel". Once You have signed into Your Forum Account You may easily make changes to Your preferences, delete board cookies, or edit or delete Your Own posts made on the forum boards. Please note that normal users cannot delete a post once someone has replied to the post.

Unfortunately, to the extent that such information is also stored in other databases, We cannot always ensure that such corrections or deletions will reach the other databases. We will use all reasonable efforts to ensure that Your information is removed from or corrected in Our records.

## 10\. SUBPOENA POLICY

We will disclose Personally Identifiable Information, after subpoena or written request, to cooperate with a law enforcement investigation. We reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that We in good faith believe to be unlawful.

If We are served with a subpoena for personal information of a user, We will provide notice to the user whose personal information is sought by the subpoena to give them the opportunity to object to the subpoena. If the user does not object to the subpoena within a specified period of time, We will comply with the terms of the subpoena. Should the user object to the subpoena in a court of law, We will abide by whatever decision is reached by such court of law.

## 11\. PUBLIC COMMUNICATIONS

We allow You to make public comments on Our Website in the form of comments on the Website and forum posts in Our Community Forum. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose Your personal information.

## 12\. SECURITY

WhatIsMyIPAddress.com has implemented and maintains reasonable security procedures and practices to protect against the unauthorized access, use, modification, destruction, or disclosure of Your personal information.

However, despite all reasonable security precautions and processes, such as password protection, encryption technology, and use of firewall technology, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure.

As a result, while We strive to protect Your Personally Identifiable Information, We cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information You transmit to or from Our Website, and You do so at Your own risk. Once We receive Your transmission, We will take reasonable precautions to protect its security on Our systems.

If You create a Forum Account with WhatIsMyIPAddress.com, Your password will be Your personal, secret entry code to Our Community Forum. When You access Your account information, it is kept on a secure server and a password is needed to access any account areas.

You can change Your password as many times as You like. We recommend that You keep Your password in a safe place and that You always sign off Your account and close Your browser window once You have finished Your visit.

These precautions will help prevent someone else from accessing Your account, especially if You share a computer with other people or use a computer in a public place such as an Internet cafe or library.

## 13\. CHILD PROTECTION

We take special care to protect the safety and privacy of children. To use, view, or access this Website, You must be at least thirteen (13) years old.

It is the policy of WhatIsMyIPAddress.com not to collect Personally Identifiable Information on any person under the age of 13 and We request that any person under age 13 not submit any Personally Identifiable Information via Our Website. If WhatIsMyIPAddress.com obtains actual knowledge that it has collected Personally Identifiable Information from a child under the age of 13, WhatIsMyIPAddress.com will immediately delete such information from its database. WhatIsMyIPAddress.com has designed this Privacy Policy in order to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).

## 14\. SALE, TRADE OR RENTAL OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION

We may sell, trade, rent, or transfer Personally Identifiable Information to third-parties. By using this Website, You consent to such sale, trade, rental, or transfer of Your Personally Identifiable Information.

LAST UPDATED: April 4, 2018.
